[ Music ]
[ 音乐 ]
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家好
My name's Paul Salzman, and my
我叫 Paul Salzman
friend Josh Ford and I are very
我和我的朋友 Josh Ford
excited to talk to you today
今天非常兴奋能来到这里
about servicing your Siri
和各位谈谈 Siri 表盘上的
shortcuts on the Siri watch
Siri 捷径服务
Last year, we released the Siri
去年 我们发布了 Siri 表盘
watch face, which has glanceable
每当抬起手腕
information and tappable
它就会根据用户
actions, sorted by their
使用习惯的相关性
relevance to the user, at every
使信息可以快速浏览
wrist raise.
并拥有触控操作
That means our users have access
这意味着我们的用户
to dynamically updated content,
不需任何配置
relevant to them throughout the
即可全天接收到
day without any configuration
随时更新的内容
And now, in watchOS 5, we are
现在 在 watchOS 5 中
very excited to add your
我们非常兴奋可以将
applications as data sources to
你的 App 作为数据源
the Siri watch face.
添加到 Siri 表盘上
The shortcuts you provide will
你提供的捷径
show up on the watch face, on
将出现在表盘上
these items that we call
或者说 在这些称之为
platters.
卡片的东西上
When the user taps on one of
当用户轻触这些卡片时
these platters, the underlying
它就会执行
shortcut will be executed.
相应的捷径操作
That can do something like
比如它可以
launching into your application
进入到你的 App 内
into a specific context, or if
具体的内容界面中去
your shortcut supports
如果你的捷径支持后台运行
background execution, we can run
我们还可以直接
that inline on the watch face.
在表盘上运行这个内联程序
That means users can take
也就是说
advantage of your application's
用户不用离开表盘
functionality without leaving
就能使用 App 的功能
So, let's take a look at what
让我们来看看
we're going to talk about today.
我们今天要讨论的内容
We're going to start off by
我们将从内容是
going over how content appears
如何在 Siri 表盘上显示开始
After that, we'll talk about the
然后 我们会讨论
Relevant Shortcut API, which is
Relevant Shortcut API
the API you use to provide
即用来给 Siri 表盘
content to the Siri watch face.
提供内容的 API
We'll also go over how you can
我们也会提到如何在你的
use this API within your iOS
iOS App 内
application to provide content
使用 API 来为你的
to the Siri watch face.
Siri 表盘提供内容
And then, I'm going to hand
之后我会把场地交给 Josh
things over to Josh, who'll talk
让他为大家介绍预测引擎
about our prediction engine, as
并让各位了解
well as give you insight as to
如何最好的利用这些 API
how best to use these API's for
来为你的 App
your application.
提供服务
So, let's talk about how content
让我们来看看
appears on the Siri watch face.
Siri 表盘如何显示内容
Everything on the Siri watch
Siri 表盘上的所有内容
face is sorted by its relevance
都是根据它和用户的相关性
to the user.
来进行排序的
The more relevant a piece of
某条内容和用户的相关性越高
content is, the higher up on the
它就会出现在
watch face it's going to appear.
表盘的更上方
And, we calculate relevance by
我们通过整合系统中
incorporating a number of inputs
大量的输入信息
across the system, like the
来计算相关性 比如
current time of day, the user's
当前的时间 用户的位置
location, their routine, and
他们的日常活动
their engagement with a given
以及他们与给定数据源的
data source.
互动情况
You'll provide this content to
你们将为我们提供
us with a relevantShortcut,
相关的捷径内容
which associates a shortcut with
而相应的捷径
UI customization, and the
会用于自定义 UI
ability to give us hints as to
并能提示我们
when to deploy your content.
何时来分配你们的内容
Now, we will derive implicit
现在 我们将根据
relevance for the shortcuts you
用户过去和
provide based off of your user's
捷径的互动
past interaction with the
获得内部的相关性
But, often you have much more
但是 你通常会有更多
insightful suggestions,
的明智建议
especially when showing
尤其是显示
glanceable information, or if
可快速浏览的消息时
you want to suggest a shortcut
或者你想推荐一个
that hasn't yet been executed by
还没被用户使用过的捷径
a user.
所以 你可以向我们提供
called relevance providers.
叫做 Relevance Providers 的东西
And, just like a first-party
而且 和第一方数据源一样
data source, users can disable
用户可以通过
or re-enable your data source in
iOS Watch App
the Siri face customization page
在 Siri 表盘上的定制页面
in the iOS Watch app.
停用或重新激活你的数据源
Now, before we get too far into
在我们深入讨论
adopting the Relevant Shortcut
Relevant Shortcut API 前
API, we want to make sure we're
我们想确认相应的捷径
relevance calculations when we
在表盘上运行与显示的同时
see how our relevant shortcuts
没有和它们的
behave and look on the watch
相关性算法相冲突
So, while we're developing,
所以 当我们开发时
we're going to want to go into
我们想进入到 iOS
the iOS Settings app, into the
设置 App 的内部
Developer's page, and find the
进入开发者界面
Shortcuts Testing section.
找到捷径测试部分
In there, we can ensure that our
这样我们可以确保
most recently provided relevant
最近提供的相关
shortcuts show up at the top of
捷径会出现在表盘的最上方
the watch face, by enabling the
这是通过允许 “Show Recent Shortcuts”
Show Recent Shortcuts option.
选项来实现的
Additionally, as we get further
此外 随着我们更多的在
into adopting this API in our
iOS App 内采用
iOS application, we can cause
此 API 我们可以
the periodic syncing of relevant
通过点击 “Force Sync Shortcut
shortcuts from the iOS device to
to Watch” 按钮来将
the watch to occur immediately
和 iOS 设备相关的捷径
Shortcuts to Watch button.
定期和 Watch 同步
So, now let's talk about
所以 现在让我们来谈谈
relevant shortcuts, and at the
Relevant Shortcut
core of a relevant shortcut, is
Relevant Shortcut 的核心就是捷径
Shortcuts encompass key
捷径包含着
functionality, within your
你的 App 内
application, that you want to
想让用户更易
make more accessible to your
获得的核心功能
And, they can access these
并且 他们能通过
shortcuts by saying key phrases
对 Siri 说出关键词
into Siri, or tapping on various
或者轻触不同的系统 UI 来访问捷径
system UI.
而在 watchOS 中
that's a platter on the Siri
那就是在 Siri 表盘
watch face.
上的一张卡片
There's a lot of in-depth
今年有很多
discussion about how to make
关于如何制作出色的
great shortcuts this year.
捷径的深入讨论
And all will give a high-level
这都将给我们一个高层次的概况
overview of how they work with a
为我们展现它们是如何
watchOS persecutive.
在 watchOS 上工作的
I highly recommend seeing the
我非常推荐大家去看一看
"Introduction to Siri Shortcuts"
"Introduction to Siri Shortcuts"
talk, and the "Building for
和 "Building for Voice with
Voice with Siri Shortcuts" that
Siri Shortcuts" 它们是
happened earlier in the
在这次大会早些时候进行的演讲
So, shortcuts can be made out of
捷径可以由
one of two things.
两种东西来组成
An NSUserActivity, which
其中之一是 NSUserActivity
represents a state within your
它代表你在 App 内
application you want to
想要让用户
accelerate users back into, or
快速返回的任务
an intent, which can execute a
或是代用户
task on your user's behalf.
执行的任务
Now, intents are really
如今 Intent 十分强大
powerful, because they can
因为它们可以
support background execution,
支持后台运行
which means that users can take
这意味着用户无需
advantage of your functionality
把 App 在前台启动
without having to launch your
就可以使用
app into the foreground.
软件的功能
In fact, users can request
实际上 用户可以从
background-capable intents that
他们的 Apple Watch
are available on their iPhone
或 HomePod 上查询
from their Apple watch or
可在其 iPhone 上支持后台运行的 Intent
And, our frameworks provide a
而且 我们框架提供了
lot of built-in intents you can
许多你立即就能
take advantage of right now,
使用的嵌入式 Intent
like sending a message, starting
比如发短信 开始体能训练
a workout, or requesting a ride.
或者请求搭车
But, new in watchOS 5, and iOS
不过 在新一代 watchOS 5 和 iOS 12 中
12, you can make your own custom
你可以制作个性化的
intents that have the
并拥有你的
functionality that your app does
App 最佳功能的 Intent
There's this awesome in-depth
Xcode 中内置了
intents definition file and
这个非常棒的深度 Intent
editor built into Xcode.
定义文件和编辑器
And, I'll give you a couple of
并且 我会给各位
pointers related to relevant
看一些有关 Relevant Shortcut 的指示器
But, I highly recommend seeing
不过 我特别推荐各位
those other talks for full
看看其他的讲座来了解
details.
全部的细节
Now, let's go over a couple of
现在 让我们来看几个
examples of how shortcuts will
当 Watch App 发出请求时
execute when requested from a
捷径将如何执行的例子
User generates their shortcut
用户通过轻点 Siri 表盘
request by tapping on the Siri
或向 Siri 说出
watch face, or by saying a key
关键的语音词汇
voice phrase to Siri, and the
来生成捷径请求
watch receives that request.
之后 Watch 会收到这一请求
It'll examine it and determine,
它会检查并确认
is there an application that's
是否有已安装并能处理这个
installed that can handle the
捷径的 App
And, in this example, yes, there
在这个例子当中
is one that's installed.
有一个已安装的软件
So, we're going to dispatch that
所以 我们会将这个
shortcut to the appropriate
捷径发送到适合的 App 上
If your shortcut is implemented
如果你的捷径
by an intent that can handle
是由一个能后台运行的
background execution, the
Intent 生成的 那么
application's intent execution
执行 App 的 Intent
will run that shortcut.
将运行这个捷径
But, if instead your shortcut is
但是 如果你的捷径
built off of a NSUserActivity,
不是基于 NSUserActivity 构建的
or an intent that can't run in
或者你的 Intent 无法
the background, the application
支持后台运行 那么 App
itself will be launched to
就会自行启动
handle the shortcut.
来处理这个捷径
When the shortcut execution is
当捷径执行完成
complete, a result will be
它会生成一个结果
generated, and then handed back
然后将结果返回给用户
Now, let's take a look at
现在 让我们来看看
another example.
另一个例子
In this case our user taps on
在这个例子中 用户轻点 Siri 表盘
key phrase to Siri to generate
或者向 Siri 说出关键词来生成
the shortcut request.
捷径请求
And, the watch will examine it.
之后 Watch 会检查这个请求
And, in this case, it'll
这种情况下
determine that there isn't an
它会确认是否有
application that's installed
已安装的能处理这个
that can handle the shortcut.
捷径的 App
So, we'll check with the phone
所以 我们会检查手机
and see if it has an app that
是否有能处理这个
can handle the shortcut.
捷径的 App
And, in this case, yes there is.
在这个例子里 手机中有这样的 App
So, we're going to forward that
所以 我们将把请求
request over to the phone.
发送至手机
And, the proper application, or
之后就会有相应的 App
intents extension will handle
或 Intent 扩展程序
execution.
来执行请求
When execution is complete, a
当请求执行完毕
result will be generated on the
手机上会生成一个结果
phone, and forward back to the
将其返回给 Watch
watch, and conveyed to the user.
再传达给用户
So, now that we understand the
那么 现在我们了解了
key concepts that make up a
构成捷径的关键概念
shortcut, and how it'll execute
以及它在 Watch 上是如何执行的
on the watch, let's talk about
下面让我们来看看
relevant shortcuts, which take
Relevant Shortcut 它可以获取你的
your shortcuts and show them on
捷径并在最相关的时刻
the watch face when they're most
将它们呈现在表盘上
We can automatically populate
我们可以根据你的捷径内容
the Siri watch face, based on
自动对 Siri 表盘中
your shortcut content.
卡片上的栏目进行填充
But, you can also customize the
不过 你也可以根据个人习惯
platter's display, which is
决定卡片的显示内容
really useful for displaying
这对一目了然地呈现信息
glanceable information.
十分有用
And, of course when your platter
当然 当你轻点卡片
is tapped, the underlying
就会执行
shortcut will be executed.
相应的隐藏的捷径
So, let's take a look at how
那么 下面让我们来看看
this will run on this watch
这在表盘上是如何运行的
If your shortcut is backed by a
如果你的捷径支持
user activity, when the user
用户活动 那么当用户
taps on it, your app will be
轻点它 你的 App
launched into the appropriate
将自动打开相关的内容
If instead, your app is-- or,
如果你的 App 或者
your shortcut is based off of
捷径不是基于 Intent 构建的
intents, when the user taps on
那么当用户轻点卡片时
the platter, we'll see this
我们将看到这样的
intent confirmation view.
Intent 确认界面
And, if they tap to confirm it,
如果用户轻点确认
if your intent runs at the
并且你的 Intent 是在后台运行的
background, we'll execute it
那么我们将内联执行该指令
If instead your intent can't run
假如你的 Intent
in the background, we'll launch
无法在后台运行 我们将启动
your application, and hand you
你的 App 并递交你的
the intent to continue
Intent 来继续执行指令
So, let's look at the API for
接下来 让我们看一下 Relevant Shortcut
Relevant Shortcuts.
的 API
At the core of a relevant
Relevant Shortcut 的核心
shortcut, of course, is a
当然就是捷径
If you want to give us hints as
如果你想提示我们
to when this content is
这一内容何时
relevant, you can provide us
会产生相关性 你可以给我们提供
relevanceProviders, which we'll
relevanceProviders
go over soon.
我们很快会介绍它
And, if you want to customize
如果你想自定义的
the UI beyond what your shortcut
UI 超出了捷径
will provide, you can give us a
可提供的范围 你可以在
defaultCardTemplate on the
watchTemplate 属性中给我们一个
watchTemplate property.
默认卡片模版
Now, once you're done creating
现在 当你创造完成了
all of your wonderful relevant
所有的 Relevant Shortcut
shortcuts, you need to let us
你需要让我们了解它们
So, you want to inform the
你要告知
default relevantShortcutStore.
默认 relevantShortcut 商店
And, the way you do that is
你可以通过提供一个数组
providing an array.
来做到这一点
And, every time you give us an
每当你提供给我们一个数组
array, it'll erase the previous
它就会清除之前
contents we had in our shortcut
Shortcut Store 内的内容
store, which is really useful
这对清除过去的
for invalidating stale relevant
Relevant Shortcut 非常有用
But, you just need to keep in
不过 你只需记住
mind to provide us all of the
为我们提供所有
relevant shortcuts we should be
需要我们考量的 Relevant Shortcut
considering.
就可以了
So, let's look at how your
让我们来看看
content will display on the
我们的内容是如何在
platter.
卡片上显示的
You can see on the top left,
你可以在左上角看到
your application's icon will be
你的 App 图标
displayed, followed by your
以及你的 App 的名称
Below that is a required title
它的下面需要一个标题字符串
string, and below that is an
再下面是可选的副标题
optional subtitle string, that
你可以用它显示
you can use for more context.
更多的文字
We'll display that in italics.
副标题的内容将用斜体显示
To the left of both of these
这些标题的左边是
strings is an optional custom
可选的自定义图像
This image supports
它支持透明图像
transparency, and automatically
而且自动采用圆角模式
You can see more about the
你可以通过 watchOS 的
dimensions of these assets by
Human Interface Guidelines
looking at the human interface
来了解更多关于
guidelines resources for
这些素材的尺寸
Now, as I mentioned, we can
正如我之前提到的 现在我们可以
automatically populate all these
自动填充所有
fields based off of the
非用户提供的捷径栏目
In the case of a custom intent,
在自定义 Intent 的情况下
every parameter combination you
你提供的每一个参数组合
supply has an associated title
都会关联一个我们可以使用的
and subtitle we can use.
标题和副标题
And, as you create your intents
而且 当你用代码生成了 Intent
in code to generate a shortcut,
并产生了一个捷径之后
you can set an image for any of
你可以用任意参数来设定图像
We will choose an image for the
我们将根据所提供的
custom image, based off of what
最详细的参数
is available on the most
来为自定义图像
specific parameter.
选择一个图像
And, the specificity of a
一个参数的具体取值
parameter is defined by the
是由你列在
order of parameters you have
Intent 定义文件
listed in your intents
内的参数所决定的
In the case of an
在 NSUserActivity 的情况下
NSUserActivity, when you're
当你通过创建你的
creating your userActivity to
userActivity 来生成
make a shortcut, you'll supply
一个捷径时
it-- userActivity type that
你要提供你在 App 的
you've listed in your app's
info.plist 中的
info.plist.
userActivity 类型
And, for us to be able to
对我们来说 要想不用
display it without a default
默认卡片模版就将其
card template, you'll need to
呈现出来 你需要给我们
give us a title on the title
在标题属性上提供一个
property.
标题的值
In iOS you can also supply a
在 iOS 中 你也可以通过
subtitle and a custom image by
创建一个 CSSearchableItemAttributeSet
creating a
来提供副标题和自定义图像
And, on that attribute set,
在该属性集上
we'll extract a subtitle from
我们将从内容描述属性中
the content description
抽取副标题
property, and the custom image
并且从 thumbnailData 属性中
from the thumbnailData property.
抽取自定义头像
When you're done configuring
当你配置完
this attribute set, set on your
这个属性集 就可以将它设置在
NSUserActivity's
NSUserActivity 的
contentAttributeSet property.
contentAttributeSet 属性中了
If you don't want to give us the
如果你不想提供给我们
content that's baked into your
整合进你的捷径的内容
shortcut, you can supply a
你可以提供一个
default card template, which has
默认卡片模版 它有
properties for each of the
卡片上每一个栏目的属性
And, depending on what we have
而且 根据我们所获取的内容
available to us, we will display
我们将展示不同的布局
You can see in the right two
大家可以看到右边的
configurations, that if no image
两个配置 如果它们未提供
is provided, we'll lay out the
图像 我们将把它的文字
text further to the left, giving
向左延伸
you more space for your words.
这给文字内容提供了更多的空间
In the bottom two cases, if
在下方的两个例子中
there's no subtitle, we'll allow
如果没有副标题
the title string to wrap from
我们会把标题字符串
the top line to the bottom line.
从顶行自动换至底行
If your shortcut is based on an
如果你的捷径是基于 Intent 构建的
intent, when a user taps on it,
当用户轻点它时
they'll see this intent
就会看到这个 Intent 确认视图
In the top left is your
左上角是你的
application's icon, which is a
App 图标
bit bigger this time, followed
它会变大一点 后面是
by your app's name.
你的 App 名称
Below that we'll display the
在此之下 我们将直接从
title and subtitle directly from
你的 Intent 的定义文件中
your intents definition file.
选取显示的标题和副标题
And, at this point, the user has
这时候 用户有
three options.
三个选项
If they want to run your intent,
如果他们想运行你的 Intent
they can click Confirm in that
可以点击中间粉色的
middle pink button.
确认按钮
If they don't want to run it,
如果他们不想运行它
they can tap dismiss or the
可以轻点忽略按钮
digital crown.
或者 Digital Crown
And then, the third option is a
第三个选项
bit more subtle.
要更为精细
Sometimes users see an intent,
有时用户看到一个 Intent
realize they want to tweak some
发现自己想对其中的一些参数
of the parameters.
做轻微调整
So, they can tap that top
那么 他们可以轻点顶端的模块
module, and we'll launch into
我们将启动你的
your application, and hand you
App 并提供
the intent you've customized.
你自定义过的 Intent
So, you can present some UI to
因此 你可以在继续
allow your users to tweak some
执行指令前 呈现给用户一些
of the parameters before
可以对某些参数
continuing execution.
稍作修改的 UI
Now, let's talk about that
现在 让我们来进一步
middle pink Confirm button a
谈谈中间的
little bit more.
粉色确认按钮
The string we show there, where
我们这里所显示的字符串
it says Action Verb, is derived
是一个操作动词
based off of the category of
它基于你在
intent you've defined in your
Intent 定义文件中
intents definition file.
定义的 Intent 类别
Additionally, that color is
此外 这个颜色是从
chosen from your application's
你的 Watch App 界面描述板里
global tint color in your watch
App 的全球色彩中
app storyboard.
选出来的
Now, it's very important to keep
要时刻记住
in mind that the intents that
你的 Watch App 内
you support in your watch app
支持的 Intent
must be a subset of the intents
必须是你的 iOS App
you support in your iOS
支持的 Intent 的子集
That means you're going to be
这意味着你将在 iOS 和 watchOS 上
sharing the same title strings,
共享同样的
and subtitle strings on iOS and
标题字符串和
watchOS.
副标题字符串
And, watchOS is a very
而 watchOS
constrained canvas.
是一个有很多约束的画板
Every word counts.
每一个字都很重要
So, we highly recommend using
因此 我们非常推荐使用
string dictionaries, with the
NSStringVariableWidthRuleType 密钥
NSStringVariableWidthRuleType
和字符串字典
That allows you to give us a
这允许你给我们
list of varying sizes of strings
许多可供我们选择的
that we can choose from,
不同大小的字符串
depending on the context we're
我们可以根据
displaying them in.
呈现内容的环境来进行选择
When providing content to
当为 watchOS 提供内容时
watchOS, we recommend supplying
我们推荐为 38 毫米 Watch
a string with a width rule of 20
提供一个宽度规则
for a 38 millimeter watch.
为 20 的字符串
And, a width rule of 24 for a 42
同时 为 42 毫米 Watch 提供
millimeter watch.
一个宽度规则为 24 的字符串
To get more information on
想了解更多关于这个
adopting this API, please see
API 的信息
the "Localizing with Xcode 9"
请观看去年大会上的
talk from last year's
"Localizing with Xcode 9" 讲座
So now, let's talk about
现在让我们来
relevance providers.
谈论一下 Relevance Provider
Relevance providers are your way
Relevance Provider 是
to give us a hint as to when we
一种提示我们
should show your content.
何时该显示内容的方法
They really let us know how we
这种方法可以让我们知道
should incorporate inputs like
我们在计算相关性时
the time of day, the user's
该如何整合内容 比如时间
location, or their routine, when
用户的位置 或他们的
calculating relevance.
日常活动
And, in fact, you can give more
而实际上 你可以在一个
than one relevance provider on a
Relevance Shortcut 种给我们
given relevance shortcut.
提供不止一个的 Relevance Provider
And, we're going to take the
我们还将利用
inner section of their output.
输出信息的内部区段
So, if you give us a relevance
所以 如果你给我们提供一个
provider that says a certain
说明某天某个时刻
time of day's very important.
很重要的 Relevance Provider
And, another one that says a
而另一个说明某个
specific location's important,
特定的位置很重要
you'll get high relevance output
当在这个时刻用户同时
when both it is that time of day
出现在这个位置时 你将得到
and the user is at that
高关联性的输出结果
If instead you want the union of
如果你想将这些
these relevance providers,
Relevance Provider 结合起来
you're going to want to provide
你需要分别提供两个
two separate relevance
Relevance Shortcut
shortcuts, each one with a
每一个都有
different relevance provider.
不同的 Relevance Provider
So, let's take a look at the
那么让我们来看一下
options we have available.
我们可用的选项
The first one is
第一个是
INDateRelevanceProvider, which
INDateRelevanceProvider
has a required startDate
它有规定的 startDate 参数
parameter, and an optional
和一个可选的
endDate parameter.
endDate 参数
When you create an instance of
当你新建一个这样的
this relevance provider, the
Relevance Provider 实例时
closer time of day gets to the
离你提供的开始时间
start that you've provided, the
越接近 那么 Provider
higher the relevance output of
输出的相关性就越高
After that time of day passes,
当那一天的那一时刻过去后
the relevance will fall off on a
其相关性就会呈曲线下滑
curve, allowing more content to
以让更多的
appear on the top of the watch
内容出现在表盘上
And, if you give us this
如果你给我们提供了
optional endDate, we'll adjust
可选的 endDate 我们会调整曲线
that curve to accommodate.
来适应信息
If your content instead is more
如果你的内容
relevant to a given location,
和指定位置更相关
you can use the
你可以使用
INLocationRelevanceProvider.
INLocationRelevanceProvider
It takes a CLRegion as its main
当你构建一个这样的实例时
parameter when you create an
它会把 CLRegion
instance of this.
作为主要参数
As the user gets closer and
当用户离这一区域
closer to that region, the
越来越近时
relevance output of this
RelevanceProvider 输出的
relevanceProvider gets higher
关联性就会变得越来越高
Now, you don't always have a
你的脑海中并不会经常出现
specific time of day, or
关联内容的
location in mind, for where your
具体时间或
content should be relevant.
或具体位置
User's schedules, their favorite
用户的日程
locations vary all over the
和他们最爱的位置
place, and you don't want to
时常发生变化
have to get in the business of
你肯定不想追踪
tracking all of this.
所有的这些信息
So, you can take advantage of
所以你可以利用
the Siri face's smarts, and use
Siri 面部智能识别并且使用
an
INDailyRoutineRelevanceProvider
where we have situations for
这里面有
both time of days that might be
用户可能喜爱的
favorite for your users, and
时刻和位置
For instance, if you have some
比如说 假如你有一些
content you want to show as a
想要在用户醒来时
daily forecast when your user
作为每日预报来显示的内容
wakes up, you don't want to have
你不必知道他们是
to know if they wake up at 5
早上五点醒还是
A.M. or 10 A.M.
上午十点醒
You should just give us the
你只需向我们提供
morning situation.
早晨的情况即可
And, if you've got a workout you
如果你想进行需要些
want to suggest that requires
运动器材的体能训练
some gym equipment, you can pass
你只要提供我们
us the gym situation.
运动的情况即可
So, now that we have all of this
现在我们的 Toolbox 里
API in our toolbox, let's build
已经有了所有的这些 API
a couple of relevant shortcuts.
下面让我们构建一些 Relevant Shortcut
In my examples we've got a
在我的例子中 我们制作了一个
hypothetical meal logging
虚拟的记录饮食的 App
application that allows users to
它可以让用户记录
log their meals, and they can
自己的饮食情况 而且他们可以
opt to do challenges.
选择做些挑战
This week's challenge, our users
在这周的挑战中 我们的用户
opted into a veggie challenge.
选择了素食挑战
So, we're going to create a user
那么 我们将为记录饮食
activity for logging meals.
创建一个用户活动
It's an activity type is
它的活动类型是
com.myapp.LogMeal.
com.myapp.LogMeal
And, because we're going to be
由于我们要在
displaying this for the dinner
晚餐时显示出来
meal, we're going to set the
我们要把用户信息
value for the meal key in our
字典内的重要内容
user info dictionary to Dinner.
设置到晚餐中
Once we have our userActivity
一旦我们设置好了 userActivity
set up, we can create a
我们就可以创建一个捷径
shortcut, and from that
从这个捷径里
shortcut, we can create a
我们就可以创建出一个
relevantShortcut.
Relevant Shortcut
Now, we want to really let our
现在 我们想让用户知道
users know that this is showing
因为他们已经
up on the watch face, because
选择了素食挑战
they've opted into the veggie
因此这一内容将在表盘上
challenge.
显示出来
So, we're going to create a
我们要制作一个
default card template to
默认卡片模版
customize their UI with Log
来用 Log Dinner 这个名字
Dinner as our title.
来作为自定义 UI 的标题
And, we're going to convey the
并且 我们会在副标题
veggie challenge in our subtitle
和自定义图像中
and our custom image.
显示素食挑战
Now, our users haven't always
我们的用户不经常
been necessarily logging their
记录自己的饮食
dinners, but they've opted into
但是他们选择了这个挑战
So, we want to give the system a
所以 我们想给系统一个提示
hint that this should be
告诉它这个内容
displayed in the evening by
应在夜间 通过在 .evening. 情景下发送
dailyRoutineRelevanceProvider
dailyRoutineRelevanceProvider
with the situation .evening.
显示出来
And now that our
现在既然我们的
relevantShortcut is configured,
Relevant Shortcut 已经配置完成了
we can pass it along to the
我们可以把它发送至
default relevantShortcutStore.
默认的 relevantShortcutStore 中
For our next example, in our
下一个例子 在我们的
application, users also have a
App 中 用户还可以
bunch of favorites they can
设定许多爱吃的
configure for snacks they eat
和经常吃的零食
often, or perhaps a breakfast
或者设置他们每天吃的早餐
So, we've created a
那么我们创建了一个
logFavoriteMealIntent.
logFavoriteMealIntent
We want a couple of these to
我们想要这些
surface on the watch face to
显示在表盘上
make it even easier for our
使用户更易记录
users to log their favorite
自己最爱的零食和饮食
So, we'll create an instance of
因此 我们将新建一个 Intent 的实例
our intent, and take one of our
拿出一个我们最爱的食物
favorites, and set it on the
在参数中将它
favorites parameter.
设置为最爱
In this case, our user likes to
这个例子中 我们的用户爱吃曲奇
We'll also set an image for that
我们也会为这一参数设置一个
parameter, so that when it shows
图像 当它出现在表盘上时
up on the watch face, they get a
用户就会有更多的
little bit more context about
相关信息来了解
what they're about to log.
他们将记录什么
From here, we can take our
从这里 我们可以采用我们的
intent and create a shortcut,
Intent 创建捷径
and from our shortcut, create a
通过捷径就可以创建一个
relevantShortcut.
relevantShortcut
At this point, we're ready to
此时 我们就准备好将
pass along our relevantShortcut
relevantShortcut 发送至
to the relevant shortcut store.
relevant shortcut store 了
We don't need a default card
我们不需要默认卡片模版
template, because the title
因为有标题字符串
strings and image, the image
和我们发送给
that we pass along to our
Intent 的图像
intent, should be sufficient.
就已经足够了
We also don't really want to
我们实在不想
provide a relevanceProvider
再提供一个 relevanceProvider
Because this is something
因为这对用户来说
habitual for our users.
是已经习以为常的事情
They log these often throughout
他们通常会全天
the day, and we can take
记录这些 我们可以利用
advantage of the Siri face's
Siri 面部预测引擎
prediction engine to show it
让它在用户最需要
when it most matters to our
的时候显示出来
And, once we're done creating
而且 尽管我们完成了
our relevantShortcuts, we're not
relevantShortcuts 的创建 但实际上到这一步
done here actually.
我们还没有彻底结束
We need to be able to handle
我们也需要有能力来处理它们
And, new in watchOS 5 is a
在新的 watchOS 5 中
method on your
在你的 WKExtensionDelegate
WKExtensionDelegate called
中有一种叫做
handle user shortcut.
处理用户捷径的方法
And, our first example, if the
来看我们的第一个例子 如果
user taps on that Siri platter,
用户轻点 Siri 上的卡片
our application will be
我们就会启动 App
launched, and we'll be handed a
接下来我们会把用户活动
user activity to this method,
传递给这个方法
whose activity type matches
这种方法的活动类型和
com.myapp.LogMeal.
com.myapp.LogMeal 是匹配的
At this point, we want to make
在这个阶段 我们想确定
sure we go into the right part
我们进入到了 App 中
of our application.
正确的部分
So, we'll jump up to the
所以我们会跳转到
rootInterfaceController, and
rootInterfaceController
push on our
进而启用
logMealInterfaceController.
logMealInterfaceController
We've got to be sure to pass
我们要确保
along that context we put into
将我们输入进用户信息字典
our user info dictionary, so we
的内容继续传递
know which meal we're about to
这样我们才能知道要记录
be logging.
哪一顿饮食
For our second example, the
来看第二个例子
common case will be that that
一般来说
background-capable intent will
能够后台运行的 Intent
execute successfully in our
可以成功在我们的
intents extension.
Intent 扩展程序中运行
But, there are a couple
不过 也有一些我们的
instances where our application
App 会
will get a callback directly.
直接收到反馈的实例
The first one being if there's
第一种是 假如在执行指令的
an error during execution, and
过程中有错误产生
we say we need to handle this
我们需要在 App 内处理它
The other one, though, might
另一种则可能
happen if the user wants to
出现在用户想要
tweak a couple of the
稍微修改一些参数时
For instance, they see that
比如 当他们想要
they're about to log a cookie,
记录一个曲奇饼
when they really know they just
但实际上吃掉了五个时
ate 5.
那么 我们要轻点顶端模块
we'll launch into your
启动你的 App
application, and you'll get a
然后你就会收到一个反馈
The userActivity you'll receive
你收到的 userActivity
will have an activity type equal
的活动类型
to the name of the class of
将和你给我们的 Intent 类
intent you gave us.
名称相同
At this point, you can extract
在这个阶段 你可以从
an interaction off of
userActivity 中抽出
userActivity, and an intent off
一个交互 和这个交互中的
of that interaction, which will
一个 Intent 它拥有
have all the parameters you set
你创建 Relevant Shortcut 时设置的
relevantShortcut.
所有参数
So, now we're ready to create
所以 每当我们的 App
relevant shortcuts whenever our
运行时 我们都可以
application has runtime.
创建 Relevant Shortcut
But, it's very important to
不过 必须注意的一点是
note, that just because your
尽管你的内容出现在
content is showing up on the
Siri 表盘上
Siri watch face, doesn't mean
但是这不一定意味着
your application is actively
你的 App 正在运行
So, to help you get more runtime
所以 为了帮助大家获得更多的
to provide relative shortcuts,
运行时间 以提供相关的捷径
we've created the
我们创建了
WKRelevantShortcutRefresh
WKRelevantShortcutRefresh
BackgroundTask.
后台任务
We'll be handing this out to
我们将把它传递给
applications that are providing
那些用户花费了时间
awesome relevant shortcuts that
观察 浏览
our users are spending time
但并没有滑开的
looking at, tapping through, but
App 的 Relevant Shortcut
When you get one of these
当你有了一个
refresh background tasks, it's
后台刷新任务
your opportunity to update the
你就可以更新支持你
data that supplies your relevant
Relevant Shortcut 的数据
shortcuts, and give us a fresh
并给我们提供一套全新的
set of relevant shortcuts.
Relevant Shortcut 了
And, on a related note, if your
顺便一提 当支持
background-capable intent
后台运行的 Intent 运行时
executes, it's inside of your
它执行在你的 Intent 扩展程序的内部
That means that if you update
这意味着如果你更新
your data store, it's possible
你的数据库存储
that your UI and your
有可能是因为你的 UI
application has become stale.
和 App 已经老化
So, in watchOS 5, we've also
所以 在 5 中
created the
我们还创建了
WKIntentDidRunRefresh
WKIntentDidRunRefresh
BackgroundTask.
BackgroundTask
And, we'll hand that to you with
并且 我们将把它同
some runtime when your intents
一些运行时间
extension completes a execution
在 Intent 扩展程序执行完
of a shortcut.
捷径之后一同传递给你
That is your opportunity to make
这样你就可以确认
sure that your UI's up to date,
你的 UI 是否是最新版本
perhaps request an updated
是否需要更新
snapshot, or reload, or extend
Snapshot 或者重装以及
your complication timeline.
扩展你的并行时间线
So, let's talk about how we can
下面让我们来看看
take advantage of these API's on
如何利用 iOS 里的这些 API
And, the great news is, with the
好消息是 除了那些
WKRefreshBackgroundTasks, we can
WKRefreshBackgroundTasks
use all of the same exact API's
我们可以在 iOS App 内
in our iOS application.
使用完全一样的 API
The relevant shortcuts we
我们在 iOS App 里
provide in our iOS app will be
提供的 Relevant Shortcut
periodically synced from the
会定期从手机
phone to the watch.
同步到 Watch
And, merged in with local,
而且考虑到
relevant shortcuts for
在表盘上显示
consideration to be displayed on
它会结合一些本地的 Relevant Shortcut
You have all of the same UI
你拥有所有相同的 UI 自定义选项
The only difference is if your
唯一的区别就在于
relevant shortcut will execute
如果你的 Relevant Shortcut 需要
back on the phone, we'll show
回到手机上执行 我们会显示
your iOS application's icon
你的 iOS App 的图像
instead of your watchOS
而不是你的 App 的图像
And now that we can be showing
既然我们可以显示
relevant shortcuts that will
在手机或 Watch 上
execute on the phone or the
运行的 Relevant Shortcut
watch, let's talk about where
让我们来看一下
they will execute when the user
当用户轻点时
taps on them.
它会在什么地方执行指令
If a relevant shortcut can be
如果一个 Relevant Shortcut 可以由
handled by an application that's
你的 Watch 在本地安装的
installed locally on your watch,
App 处理
regardless of where it came
不论它从哪里来
from, we're going to execute it
我们都会在
in the watchOS application.
App 内执行它
That gives the user the best
这可以给予用户
experience and the lowest
最佳的体验和最少的延迟
You can ensure that your watchOS
你可以通过确认
application supports execution
用户活动的活动类型是否在
of a shortcut by making sure the
info.plist NSUserActivityTyped 序列里
user activity's activityType is
来确保你的 App
in your info.plist,
支持某个捷径的执行指令
Or, if it's an intent, that your
或者 你的 Intent
intent is listed in your intents
在你的 Intent 扩展程序列表上
If instead there is no
如果除了 iOS 上
application installed that can
没有其他已安装的 App
handle your shortcut, except on
能处理你的捷径
iOS, we'll execute it back on
我们将把它返回手机运行
the phone, even if your phone
即使你的手机
isn't near the user.
不在用户附近
Now, because we can be executing
鉴于我们现在可以把内容
content back on the phone, we
返回到手机上执行
want to make sure that users
我们想确保用户
don't tap on a platter, and then
不会轻点卡片 然后
are immediately told to go find
被立即告知去拿自己的手机
their phone.
所以 我们有一些关于
about the type of shortcuts that
我们愿意在手机上执行的
will execute back on the phone
捷径类型的相关规则
Requirements are that they're
要求就是它们是
intent-based.
基于 Intent 构建的
They handle background
它们会处理后台运行的执行指令
And, they don't require access
而且 它们不需要
to protected data.
保护数据准入
And, that's the data that you
即手机锁屏时
keep encrypted when the phone is
你要加密的数据
The way you can ensure that your
确认你的内容是否
content meets these requirements
符合要求的方法就是
is by taking a look at the
查看你自定义 Intent
parameter combination in your
里的参数组合
custom intent, and ensuring that
并确保它支持后台运行
And, looking at your overall
查看你所有的
custom intent and seeing if you
自定义 Intent 看看你采用的
have any authentication
方式有没有什么
restrictions you've applied.
验证限制
There are three options here,
这里有三个选项
and we support the first two.
我们支持前两种
The first one is that there are
第一种里面没有
no restrictions.
任何限制
The second one says that you are
第二种显示当你的设备锁住时
restricted while the device is
你被限制住了
locked, which means that at
这意味着至少要
least the watch has to be
解锁 Watch
unlocked for us to execute.
我们才能执行它
And the final one is Restricted
最后一种是
While Locked, or Protected Data
锁定时限制 或者
is Unavailable.
保护数据不可用
Now that you have all this
现在各位已经了解了所有
build some awesome shortcuts
在 Watch 和手机上
from both the watch and the
创建优秀的捷径
phone.
需要的信息
So, I'd like to hand things over
下面 我将会把场地交给 Josh
to Josh to talk a little bit
他将为大家介绍
more about our prediction
更多关于预测引擎的内容
engine.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Paul.
&gt;&gt; 感谢 Paul
Good morning.
早上好
My name is Josh, and I am an
我叫 Josh
engineer on the watchOS team.
我是团队的一名工程师
And, we're really excited to see
我们很开心能制作出多种
the kinds of relevant shortcuts
呈现在用户的
that you can surface on the Siri
Siri 表盘上的 Relevant Shortcut
So, Paul just walked you through
Paul 刚刚为大家介绍了
some of the API's and different
一些 API 的内容
ways that you can provide your
以及向系统提供你的
relevant shortcuts to the
Relevant Shortcut 的不同方式
Now, I want to talk about how
现在 我想介绍下系统
the system predicts your
是如何预测你的
relevant shortcuts, and the
Relevant Shortcut 的
things that you can do to ensure
以及你可以做些什么
the system surfaces your content
来确保系统能在
when it's most appropriate to
最恰当的时候向用户呈现你的内容
It's like Paul talked about
正如 Paul 刚刚谈到的
earlier, content on the Siri
Siri 表盘上的内容
watch face is ordered by
是根据其对用户的
relevance to the user.
相关性来排序的
At a wrist raise, we want to be
每当用户抬起手臂时
surfacing the content the user
我们想给他们呈现
cares about most.
他们最关心的内容
Whether that be based on the
不论是根据当前的
current time, location, or other
时间 地点 还是整个
factors from across the system.
系统内的其他因素而产生的
And, to figure out what content
为了解用户
the user cares about, we're
最关心什么内容
looking at how they interact
我们需要看一下他们在
with the different platters on
Siri 表盘上是如何
the Siri watch face.
与不同卡片进行互动的
What things are they tapping on?
他们在轻点什么内容呢
What things are they spending a
他们花费大量时间
lot of time looking at?
观看的是什么呢
And, what things are they
他们为寻找其他内容
scrolling past to find other
而滑过的又是些什么呢
And, we use all this information
我们用所有的这些信息
to understand what are the
来了解用户抬起手臂时
different platters that the user
想要立刻看到
wants to see right on a wrist
不同的卡片是什么
And so, because we're trying to
由于我们试着再次显示
user cares about most, you want
用户最关心的内容
to make sure that you're
你需要确保你提供在
providing relevant, engaging
Siri 表盘上的内容
content to be surfaced on the
是相关的
Siri watch face.
并且足够吸引人
So, let's talk a little bit more
下面 让我们进一步谈谈
about how we actually put your
如何把你的
relevant shortcuts on the Siri
Relevant Shortcut 显示在 Siri 表盘上
So, like Paul mentioned earlier,
正如 Paul 之前提到的
the first step is you need to
第一步 你需要给系统
provide your relevant shortcuts
提供你的 Relevant Shortcut
to the system, into the
你需要提供到
defaultRelevantShortcutsStore.
默认的 Relevant Shortcuts Store
Once you've provided your
一旦你提供了你的
relevant shortcuts, we can run
Relevant Shortcut 我们就可以
them through our machine
通过我们的
learning model to figure out
机器学习模型来弄清
what is the best way to be
向用户呈现
surfacing your relevant
Relevant Shortcut 的
shortcuts to the user.
最佳方式是什么
So, let's look at what we take
那么 让我们来看看我们在这个
into account inside of this
模式里都考虑到了什么因素
So, the first thing that we look
我们看到的第一个就是
at is your relevance providers.
你的 Relevance Provider
This is your way to provide
这是你向系统提供
additional context to the system
我们没有的
that we wouldn't otherwise have.
附加语境的方式
This might be a concrete time,
可能是一个具体的时间
location, or other context.
位置或其他语境
We also look at past behavior.
我们也会查看用户过去的行为
So, how has the user interacted
那么 用户之前是如何
with this relevant shortcut
与这个 Relevant Shortcut 互动的呢
Is it something they're spending
它是用户花费大量时间
a lot of time tapping on and
在表盘上轻点
looking at on the watch face?
并浏览的那个吗
Or, something that they're
或者 是他们为寻找
scrolling past to find something
更有趣内容而滑过的那个
We also look at a number of
我们在众多其他因素中
different factors from across
还看了系统内的
the system, such as, you know,
许多不同的因素 比如说
the current time, current day of
当前的时间 星期几
user's routine, among a number
当前的位置
of other factors.
用户的日常活动
And, take all this into account
将这些都考虑到
to try to better understand what
可以更好的了解
is the context under which the
当用户想要和特定的
user wants to interact with the
捷径互动时
particular shortcut.
的语境应该是什么
And, it's also worth noting that
还值得注意的一点是
this model is secure and
这个模型对每个用户都很安全
personalized to each user.
并且可以自定义的
All of our learning happens
我们所有的学习都是
on-device, and we're building a
在设备上进行的 并且我们正在制作
model for each and every single
一个可以针对每一个用户
user of the Siri watch face.
和 Siri 表盘的模型
The way that you interact with
你和表盘互动的方式
the watch face may be different
也许和我与表盘
from the way that I interact
互动的方式有所不同
And, once we have this model
一旦我们有了这个已训练模型
trained we can then take your
我们就可以运行你的
relevant shortcuts, and again,
Relevant Shortcut
surface them on the Siri watch
并且根据它们对用户的
face based on their relevance to
相关性把它们再次显示在 Siri 表盘上
If you attended some of the
如果你之前听过一些
previous shortcut talks, you may
关于捷径的讲座
have heard about donations.
那你可能听说过捐赠
This is your way to indicate to
这是你给系统指示的方式
the system what the user's doing
来让它知道用户在你的
within your app.
App 内做什么
And, although they don't
尽管实际上它们不会在
actually surface within the UI
Siri 表盘的 UI 里
of the Siri watch face, we take
显示出来 当我们想要
them into account when trying to
了解用户过去的行为时
understand the user's past
我们还是会将其考虑进去
So, again, donations are your
再次强调
way to indicate important tasks,
捐赠是指示重要任务
or other information about what
或其他关于用户
users are doing inside of your
在你的 App 内的活动信息
applications, and providing that
并将其提供给系统的重要方式
And, by giving this information
通过向系统提供这一信息
to the system, we can understand
我们可以明白并学会
and learn patterns in the user's
用户行为当中存在的模式
So, if the user, for example, is
例如 如果用户
looking or performing the same
每天都在同一个时间观看
action at the same time every
或在相似的位置
single day, or around similar
做出相同的动作
locations, the system can pick
系统就会挑出这些模式
up on these patterns, and again,
然后在最合适的时候
surface the relevant shortcuts
让它们出现在
when they're appropriate to your
Relevant Shortcut 中
So, if you're using
所以 如果你在用
NSUserActivities to represent
NSUserActivities 来显示
your donations, there's a few
你的捐赠
things you need to do to be able
为了向系统提供你的捐赠
to provide those donations to
你需要了解
the system.
以下的内容
The first is you need to set
首先你需要把
both these properties to "true"
这些属性在你的 NSUserActivity
in your NSUserActivity, the
eligibleForPrediction
eligibleForPrediction and
和 eligibleForSearch 中
eligibleForSearch.
设置为 "true"
Next, you need to make sure that
接下来 你需要在你的
your user activity is supported
info.plist 内指示
by an application, by indicating
来确保有一个 App
that within your info.plist.
支持你的用户活动
And, finally you want to make
最后 你想要确认
sure that you're donating these
无论用户在何时
user activities whenever this
看到了这条内容
piece of content is visible to
你都可以捐赠这些
the user, so the system can
用户活动 这样一来 系统就可以
patterns.
开始挑选模式
And so, to provide that
为了能够进行捐赠
donation, there's a method on
在 NSUserActivity 上
NSUserActivity, becomeCurrent,
有一个方法叫做 becomeCurrent
that allows you to donate to the
它允许你向系统进行捐赠
New in watchOS 5, though, there
不过 在新的 5 中
is this method
还有一个方法是
updateUserActivity on
updateUserActivity
WKInterfaceController, where you
它存在于 WKInterfaceController 上
can attach your user activity to
你可以在这上面将你的用户活动
an interfaceController, and
附加到一个 interfaceController 上
whenever this
每当用户见到这个 interfaceController
the user, the system will
系统就会自动
automatically be donating the
代你捐赠用户活动
This is similar to the API's
这和我们在 iOS 上
that we have over on iOS, on
UIViewController 中的 API
UIViewController, and
以及 UIResponder 上的 API 相似
UIResponder, where you can, kind
你可以在这些上面
of, attach an NSUserActivity to
给你的 UI 附加
a piece of your UI.
NSUserActivity
And so now, this is the
那么 这就是
recommended way to be providing
我们推荐的在  上进行
NSUserActivity donations on
NSUserActivity 捐赠的方式
If your shortcuts are backed by
如果有一个 Intent 支持你的捷径
an intent, you can provide those
你可以通过使用
intent donations by using the
INInteraction API
INInteraction API.
来进行 Intent 捐赠
So, if you attended any of the
所以 如果你之前参加过
previous shortcut talks, this
别的有关捷径的讲座
probably looks familiar to you.
你可能会对这个很熟悉
But, to provide this donation,
不过 要想进行这个捐赠
first you create your intent,
首先你要创建你的 Intent
and adjust any parameters as
并且调整每一个参数
they're necessary for what the
因为它们对用户在你的 App 内
user just did within your app.
进行的活动而言十分重要
Next, you create your
接下来 你要用 Intent
INInteraction with intent, and
创建你的 INInteraction
call the donate method when
并且在用户做出这一
users perform this particular
特定互动时 调用捐赠方法
The other thing to look out for,
另一个值得注意的是
is this primary shortcut type
这个主要的捷径类型
for when we're making watchOS
我们在作出预测时要用到它
And so, let's take a look at
那么 让我们来看一下这一内容
Inside of the Xcode intents
在 Xcode Intent editor 中
editor, you'll notice that
你会发现
there's a field to select the
有一栏可以选择
primary shortcut type.
主要的捷径类型
So, this allows you to indicate
它允许你向系统发出指示
to the system, like, kind of,
例如 你的 App 最关键的
your app.
使用案例
And so, let's talk more about
下面让我们来进一步看看
what that means.
这是什么意思
So, by indicating the primary
通过指定主要的捷径类型
shortcut type, you're, kind of,
你就像是在
telling the system what are the
告诉系统 你所认为
use cases that you think your
用户最关心的
users care about most.
使用案例是什么
And, this helps us expedite our
这可以帮我们的
learning process.
学习模型加速
You can indicate one of these
你可以指示任意一个这些你已经
per intent that you've defined.
定义的 Intent
And, for the best performance,
为达到最佳性能
the parameter combination, the
参数组合
selection, have a subset of the
和选择 都会有一个
parameters that you're providing
你在 Relevant Shortcut
in your relevant shortcuts.
提供的参数的子集
And, we'll walk through a couple
接下来 我们将展示几个例子
of examples to try to better
来让大家理解
understand what that means.
这是什么意思
But, by giving this information
不过 通过向系统传递这一信息
to the system, we can much more
我们可以在用户行为中
quickly pick up on patterns in
更快地挑出相应模式
the user behavior, and much more
更快地知道
quickly understand what are the
用户最想要的
relevant shortcuts that the user
Relevant Shortcut 是什么
So, first up, we have this
首先 我们有一个
Messaging app.
叫 Messaging 的 App
And so, this is something that
我和 Paul 已经
Paul and I have been using for a
用了一阵这个软件
while now, so every morning
每天早上
we're sending messages back and
我们都会反复地发短信
Sometimes it's in preparation
有时候它会准备好
for this talk, and other times
开始这样的对话
it's about what cookies we want
而有时候则是关于我们午饭要吃
to get at lunch.
哪一种曲奇饼
And so, this app has gone ahead
这个 App 已经采用了
and adopted Siri shortcuts.
Siri 捷径
And, they defined a couple
并且 他们定义了一些
different parameters that their
他们 App 支持的
app supports.
不同的参数
So, the first one is the
第一个是接受者
So, who am I sending a message
我的信息是发给谁的呢
to?
第二个是信息
So, what is the content of the
那么 我想发送的
message I'm trying to send?
信息内容是什么呢
So, like I mentioned before,
正如我前面提到的
right, Paul and I are using this
不错 我和 Paul 每一天的早晨
app every single morning, but
都在使用这个 App
the actual content of the
但是我们发送的
messages that we're sending
实际内容
varies from day to day.
每天都不一样
So, because of this, this may
所以 由于这一原因
not make a good candidate for
这可能不是主要的捷径类型
the primary shortcut type.
的最佳选择
It's going to take a lot longer
系统会需要更长的时间
before the system can, kind of,
才能明白
understand what are the
我想要的
shortcuts I'm trying to perform.
捷径是什么
Whereas, Paul and I are having
鉴于我和 Paul
very consistent conversations,
经常联系
so the system can really quickly
所以系统可以十分迅速地
pick up on this pattern, that
挑出这一模式
every morning, I'm sending
即我每天早上都
messages to Paul.
给 Paul 发短信
Another little more interesting
有一个更有趣的例子
example, is this app that I use
就是我每天早晨我用来
to order my morning coffee.
点咖啡的这个 App
And again, this app has gone and
这个 App 同样
adopted Siri shortcuts.
采用了 Siri 捷径
So, they support a couple
他们支持几个
different parameters.
不同的参数
The first one is the type of
第一个是我想买的
coffee I want to buy.
咖啡种类
The next one is the condiments,
下一个是调味品
so do I want cream or sugar?
我想加奶油还是加糖呢
And, finally, the location that
最后一个是
I want to pick my coffee up
我想去哪里取我的咖啡
So, every morning I use this app
所以 我每天都用这个 App
and go place an order for my
去一个地方点我的
morning coffee.
早间咖啡
But, depending on where I have a
但是 这要视我在哪里
meeting, the location that I
开会而定
want to pick my coffee up from
我想取咖啡的位置
will change from day to day.
会逐日改变
Maybe I'm going to Infinite
可能我会去 Infinite Loop
Loop, or Apple Park, or up to
或者 Apple Park
San Francisco, and I want to
或者洛杉矶
pick up my coffee at, you know,
而且我想要在最近的店里
the closest store.
取我的咖啡
So, again, because there's a lot
所以 由于位置变动的
of variability in the location,
可能性很大
this may not make a good
这可能并不是
candidate for the primary
主要捷径类型的最佳选择
It's going to take a lot longer
系统可能也需要
for the system to, kind of,
更长的时间来
understand the patterns in my
了解我行为
behavior.
中的模式
Whereas, the actual order that I
然而 我每一次
place is the same thing every
下单的内容
single time.
都是相同的
I always order a latte with the
我总是点一杯加等量
same amount of cream and same
奶油和糖的拿铁
So, this does make a really
这可以是主要的
great candidate for the primary
捷径类型的
shortcut type.
一个最佳选择
And, coffee-- it's on its own,
而且 咖啡本身
might be too generic, right?
可能太普通了 对吧
The coffee plus the condiment
加点调味品的咖啡
might make a better primary
可能是更好的主要捷径类型
And so, that is how you can
这就是你如何
provide information from within
在 App 内提供
your apps about what users are
用户在做什么这一信息的方式
So, now let's talk about how we
现在 让我们来谈谈我们将如何
predict your relevant shortcuts.
预测你的 Relevant Shortcut
And, to talk about this, we have
谈到这个内容
a couple different apps that
我们将看下几个
we're going to be looking at.
不同的 App
The first one is this recipes
第一个是这个叫 Recipes 的 App
app.
我每一天都用这个 App
provides me suggestions for
来为我提供我可能
recipes that I might want to
想尝试的食谱推荐
Next, we have this fitness
下一个是这个叫
trainer app that provides me a
Fitness Trainer 的 App
nice reminder to go out and do
它会提醒我外出
my evening run.
在晚上跑跑步
And finally, there's this travel
最后是这个叫
guide app that tries to surface
Travel Guide 的 App
interesting locations of
它会在我外出时 或我出现在
interest while I'm out and about
有趣的地点附近时
so I can make sure to go check
出现在屏幕上 这样我就可以去到
them out.
那些地方
And so, each of these three
这三个 App 中的每一个
different apps falls into one of
都会属于
these, kind of, three different
我们的三种分类里的
categories that we have.
其中一个我们把第一个称之为
"Downtime."
"Downtime"
And so, this is something that
它没有与其相关的
doesn't have a concrete time or
具体的时间
location associated with it.
或具体的位置
When I want to interact with
我想和这个
this recipes app may vary from
Recipes App
when you want to interact with
互动的时间
this particular app.
并不固定
Whereas, this fitness trainer
然而 这个 Fitness Trainer
app has a very concrete time
App 有一个非常
associated with it, right?
具体的时间 对吧
I've gone and configured that 8
我已经将晚上八点
P.M. is the perfect time to be
设置为在表盘上
surfacing this reminder to me.
提醒我的最佳时间了
And, by giving this information
通过传给系统这一信息
to the system, we can much more
我们可以更精确地将
accurately rank this particular
这一特定的 Relevant Shortcut
relevant shortcut against
与我们需要考虑的
everything else that we have to
其他因素进行排序
Similarly, this travel guide app
同样 这个 Travel Guide App
knows where they want to be
也知道它该何时
surfacing their particular
显示其相应的
relevant shortcuts, right?
Relevant Shortcut 对吧
They know all the locations of
它知道用户感兴趣的所有位置
interest, in this case,
在这个例子中
Golden Gate Park.
即金门公园
And again, by passing that
再次 通过传递给系统
information to the system, we
这一信息
can much more accurately predict
我们可以预测特定的
the relevance of this particular
捷径的相关性
And, to provide this additional
要向系统提供
context to the system, whether
这样的附加语境
that be a concrete time,
不论是具体的时间
location, or other information,
地点 或是其他的信息
you can provide that through the
你都可以通过
relevanceProvider API.
RelevanceProvider API 来提供
And so, this allows you to
这就允许你
indicate hints to the system at
在你的内容对用户
when your content is most
最具重要性时
important to your users.
向系统发出指示
It also allows you to surface
它也允许你向用户显示
new content that users may not
他们之前可能没见过的
have seen before.
一些新内容
Since you're providing this
既然你向系统提供了
additional hints to the system,
这些附加提示
we don't need to have seen as
在系统确信这是用户
much of the user's past behavior
最感兴趣的事情之前
system becomes confident that
我们无需看到过多
this is something the user cares
用户过去的行为与连贯性
But, it's also important to keep
不过 我们一定要记住
in mind that user engagement is
在每一个过程都要
taken into account at every step
考虑用户的参与度
If you provide relevance
不论你是否提供了
providers or not, we want to
Relevance Provider
make sure that the content that
我们都想确定
we're surfacing is stuff that
我们所显示的内容
the user cares about.
正是用户最关心的内容
So, let's take another look at
下面 让我们再来看一下
this recipes app.
这个 Recipes App
So, like what we talked about
就像我们之前提到的
earlier, there's not really a
它没有一个
concrete time or location
与之相关的具体的
associated with it, right?
时间或位置 对吧
The time that I want to interact
我想和这个 App
with this app may be for cooking
互动的时间可能是
dinner, whereas for you it might
做晚饭的时候 然而对你而言可能是
be for cooking lunch.
做午饭的时候
And so, in this case, we may
那这样一来
actually indicate an empty set
我们可能实际上在指示
of relevanceProviders.
Relevance Provider 的一个空集
And, in this case, the system
这样 系统将基于
will determine the relevance of
用户之前与这个捷径
this particular shortcut based
互动的情况
on how the user's interacted
来确定这一特定捷径
with it before.
的相关性
So, for me, I always use this
于我而言 我经常在
around 7 P.M. because that's
晚上七点左右使用它
when I go cook dinner, so that's
因为我在这个时间做晚饭
when the system will start to
所以这也是系统把这个
surface this particular relevant
Relevant Shortcut 显示在表盘上的时间
If we take a look, however, at
然而 如果我们看一下
this fitness trainer app, which
这个 Fitness Trainer App
does have a concrete time
它有与之相关的具体时间
associated with it, you can
你可以通过
provide that by creating a
创建一个 dateRelevanceProvider
dateRelevanceProvider, and in
来提供这个时间
this case providing the 8 P.M.
在这里即把晚上八点
start time.
作为显示时间
And, by giving this information
通过向系统传递这一信息
to the system, we will surface
我们会在一天当中的
this content around a specific
某个特定时间附近
time of day.
显示这个内容
And, as you move closer and
当时间越来越接近
closer and closer to 8 P.M.,
晚上八点
this content becomes more and
这一内容对用户的相关性
more relevant to the user.
也就越来越高
So, let's look at what-- that.
那么让我们来看一下
So, here's a couple cards that I
这是我的 Siri 表盘上
might have on my Siri watch
可能会有的几张卡片
face.
第一个是日历 它提醒我
Calendar for a prep meeting for
要为这个讲座进行一个预备会议
this talk.
下一个是我使用的一个 App
gives me interesting tidbits of
它会给我一些太空新闻的趣闻
And finally, we have this
最后 来看一下这个
fitness trainer app, so let's
Fitness Trainer App
focus in on that.
让我们来详细了解一下它
So, I just woke up, I'm getting
当我醒来
ready for my day.
准备开始新的一天
You know, it's, kind of, 8 A.M.
时间大概是早上八点
And so, you can see that this
你可以看到这个
fitness trainer app is actually
Fitness Trainer App 实际上
already starting to surface on
已经显示在 Siri 表盘上了
We want to make sure that users
我们想确保用户知道
are, kind of, aware of all the
他们在这一整天中
things they have going on during
都需要做哪些事情
the course of the day, but it's
不过它会显示在
kind of placed much lower on the
相对下面一点的位置
face.
对于用户而言 这件事
to the user right now.
目前并不是最紧要的
But, as we start moving
但是 当我们已经
throughout the day, right, that
在进行一天的活动时
calendar event that I had is no
日历上的事件
longer relevant to me.
对我而言就不再相关了
And so, this fitness trainer
那么 Fitness Trainer
suggestion will start to bubble
的建议就会在表盘
up the face, right?
上方出现 对吧
We're getting closer and closer
随着我们离晚上八点
to 8 P.M. This content is
越来越近 这个内容对我也就
becoming more important to me.
越来越重要
And, once we finally reach 8
当时间终于来到晚上八点
P.M., right, this is the most
它也就成了
important thing to me right now.
对我最重要的事情
Want to make sure I don't forget
它想确保我没有忘记
to go for my run.
要去跑步这件事
So, it'd be surfaced up at the
所以 它就会在 Siri
top of the Siri watch face.
表盘的顶部显示
Now, let's take a look at the
现在 让我们来看一下
travel guide app, which again is
Travel Guide App
trying to surface content around
它也是要在用户出现在感兴趣的
interesting locations of
有趣位置附近时
interest the user.
显示内容
And, as you may have guessed,
各位可能已经猜到
you can provide this information
你可以用一个
to the system using a
locationRelevanceProvider
locationRelevanceProvider.
向系统提供信息
In this case, near Golden Gate
在这个例子中就是
Park.
金门公园
And, by providing this
通过向系统
information to the system, we
提供这一信息
will automatically be surfacing
当用户开始向
this content when the user
金门公园靠近时
starts getting close to Golden
我们就会自动显示
Gate Park.
这一内容
And, again, as the user gets
当用户离金门公园
closer and closer and closer to
越来越近
Golden Gate Park, this content
这一内容对用户来说
becomes more relevant to them.
也就越来越相关
So, if I just arrive up in San
所以 假如我刚到洛杉矶
Francisco, you can see that
你可以看到
we're already starting to
我们已经开始显示
surface this suggestion to go
建议用户去
check out Golden Gate Park.
金门公园的内容了
It's displayed lower on the
该内容会在表盘下方显示
face, because it's not the most
因为现在对我来说
pressing thing to me right now.
这并不是最要紧的事
But, we want to make sure that
但我们想确保用户
the user is aware about this.
了解到这一内容
And, as I move closer and closer
而且 随着我越来越靠近
to Golden Gate Park, this
金门公园
content becomes more relevant to
直到我最终到达金门公园
me, until I've finally arrived,
这一内容呈现与我越来越相关的趋势
and I can really easily tap on
我可以很容易地轻点
this to dive into more details,
这个内容来了解更多详细内容
and check out what are the
并查看我在金门公园都可以
Golden Gate Park.
做些什么
When you're creating your
当你在创建你的
locationRelevanceProviders, you
locationRelevanceProviders 时
provide to the system a
你要给系统提供一个 CLRegion
And so, this allows you to
这样 你就可以
indicate two important
指明两个重要的属性
The first is the actual
第一个是实际坐标
you're interested in surfacing
你想在显示你的内容
your content, along with the
的同时显示半径
So, how close does the user need
那么 用户到底需要
to be before this content is
离这些位置多近才能获得
relevant to them?
相关的内容呢
There's also a couple properties
CLRegion 里还有几个参数
in CLRegion that you can use to,
你可以用它们
kind of, adjust how the system
调整系统理解你的
interprets your region.
区域的方式
The first one is notifyOnEntry.
第一个是 notifyOnEntry
So, as the name might suggest,
所以 顾名思义
the system waits until the user
在这条内容与用户产生相关性之前
has entered into this region
系统会一直等待
before this piece of content
直到用户进入
becomes relevant to the user.
这一区域
Similarly, there's a
同样 你也可以设置
notifyOnExit property that you
notifyOnExit 属性
can set, where the system will
在这个属性里
wait until the user has left
在该内容与用户关联之前
this particular region before
系统会一直等待
this content becomes relevant.
直到用户离开这个区域
We actually use both these two
实际上 我们将这两个属性
properties with the existing
与现有的基于 Siri 表盘的
location based reminders on the
位置提醒一起使用
Siri watch face, to get, kind
以获得一种类似于
of, a geofencing-like behavior.
地理围栏的特性
By default on CLRegion, both
CLRegion 上默认将
these properties are set to
这些属性都设定为 "true"
And, in that case, we'll
这样一来 我们就可以
smoothly interpolate the
根据用户离
relevance based on how close the
某一特定地点的距离
user is to a particular
顺利地把相关性内插进来
And so, creating your CLRegion
这样 制作 CLRegion
is really easy.
就十分简单了
In this example, we're creating
在这个例子中 我们是在
one around Apple Park, so I've
Apple Park 附近制作
brought in the coordinates for
所以我同时置入了
Apple Park, along with the
Apple Park 的坐标和它的半径
radius.
那么 我需要离这里多近呢
In this case, 2 kilometers.
在这个例子中是两公里
Next, I will go adjust the
下一步 我将调整 notifyOnEntry
notifyOnEntry, notifyOnExit
因为 notifyOnExit 属性
properties as they make sense
对我的用例有很大帮助
And, once I have my region fully
一旦我把我的区域全部
configured, I can really easily
配置完毕 我就可以十分轻松地
create a
创建一个
locationRelevanceProvider.
locationRelevanceProvider
A couple of quick notes about
我有几条关于
the locationRelevanceProvider.
locationRelevanceProvider 的提示
In order to use it, your app
为了使用它
needs location authorization,
你的 App 需要位置授权
otherwise we're going to ignore
否则我们会忽略
this particular
这一特殊的
locationRelevanceProvider.
locationRelevanceProvider
And, to preserve user battery
而且 为延长用户的电池寿命
life, the number of location
一小时内我们获取的
updates we get during the course
位置更新数量
of an hour is limited, so keep
是有限的
that in mind.
请记住这一点
So, that's some of the ways that
所以 这些是你可以向系统
you can provide concrete times
提供具体时间
and locations to the system.
和位置的一些方式
Now, let's talk about what you
下面让我们来看看
can do to try to provide
该如何向用户提供
personalization.
个性化服务
So, we have this
我们有这个
dailyRoutineRelevanceProvider.
dailyRoutineRelevanceProvider
And so, like Paul mentioned
那么 正如 Paul 之前提到的
earlier, this allows you to
它允许你在有意义的
surface content at meaningful
时间或位置为用户
times or locations to the user.
呈现相关内容
And, these times and locations
这些时间和位置
are personalized to each and
对每一位 Siri 表盘的
every single user of the Siri
的用户都是个性化定制的
So, the first situation that
那么 我们第一个
we'll talk about is the morning
要讨论的情景是早晨
This allows you to surface
这一情景允许你
content right when the user
在用户早晨醒来时
wakes up in the morning.
正确显示内容
We actually already used this
实际上我们已经将其用于
for the existing first-party
Siri 表盘上现有的
weather data source on the Siri
第一方天气数据源上了
watch face, so we can provide
因此 我们可以在一天的
the user a nice summary of the
开始之际给用户提供
forecast at the beginning of the
一份天气预报
day, and it quickly dismisses,
之后它会很快消失
making room for other content
来为用户可能感兴趣的
they might be interested in.
其他内容腾出空间
We also have an evening
我们也有夜晚的情景
And so, this allows us to
这一情景允许我们在
surface content before the user
用户上床睡觉前
goes to bed.
显示相关内容
So, we use this one for the new
我们将其用在了 5 的
heart rate card in watchOS 5, so
新版心率卡中
that we can provide the user a
以便我们能全天为用户
summary of their heart rate
提供他们心率活动
activity throughout the day.
的整体情况
And, creating a
而且 创建 dailyRoutineRelevanceProvider
really easy.
变得非常简单
You've just got to specify which
你只需指定
situation you're interested in.
你最感兴趣的情景
So, in this case, we can really
那么这样一来
easily create a
我们就可以轻松地创建一个
dailyRoutineRelevanceProvider to
dailyRoutineRelevanceProvider
surface content right when the
在用户醒来时
user wakes up.
正确地显示内容
And, the behavior for both these
这两种情景的特性
two situations is very similar
都和 dateLocation
to a dateLocation-- or a
或者说 dateRelevanceProvider
dateRelevanceProvider.
特别相似
Except that the system is
除了系统是
automatically figuring out what
自动计算出我们应该
are the dates that we should be
在何时显示
surfacing this content.
这一内容之外
We also have a few situations
我们还提供了一些
available to you that allow you
允许你在重要的位置
to surface content in meaningful
向用户显示相关内容
locations to the user, whether
的情景 无论是
that be home, work, school, or
家 工作地点 学校
when the user arrives to the
或是当用户到达健身房
And again, creating one of these
创建一个
dailyRoutineRelevanceProviders
dailyRoutineRelevanceProviders
is really easy.
非常简单
You just need to specify which
你只需指定
situation you're interested in.
你感兴趣的情景
And, for all of these
对于所有的这些情景
situations, the behavior of this
这个 relevanceProvider 的特性
again to a
还是和 locationRelevanceProvider 一样
except that the system is
除了系统是代你
automatically figuring out the
自动计算出位置
locations on your behalf.
这一点的
And so, as the user gets closer
所以 随着用户
to these locations, your content
靠近这些位置 你的内容
will become more relevant to
对用户来说
your users.
也愈加相关
So, that is some of the insight
所以 这就是我们关于
into how we predict your
如何预测你 Siri 表盘上的
relevant shortcuts on the Siri
Relevant Shortcut 的一些见解
And, some of the things that you
你还可以通过这些
can do to provide additional
来向系统提供
context to the system so that we
附加语境 以便我们能在
can surface your content when
最恰当的时间
it's most appropriate.
显示你的内容
Now, let's talk about how you
现在 让我们来看看
can build a great experience on
该如何在 Siri 表盘上
the Siri watch face.
提供绝佳的体验
So, we've been working on the
我们已经对 Siri 表盘
Siri watch face for a while now.
进行了很长时间的研究
And, we've learned quite a few
这一路以来
things along the way.
我们学到了很多
First one of those things is
首先就是 我们认为
there's kind of, two high-level
Siri 表盘上
categories of content that we
有两个高级内容分类
think works great on the Siri
特别方便使用
The first one of those is
其一就是可以
glanceable information.
可快速查看的信息
So, being able to really easily,
我们可以在
on a wrist raise, get a snippet
抬起手腕时 轻松获得自己
of information that I care
最想要的一条信息
about, and being able to tap on
并且可以在合适的时间
it when it's appropriate to dive
轻点以了解
into more details.
更多细节
The second is tappable actions.
第二个是轻点动作
So, being able to really easily,
我们可以在
from my watch face, tap on a
表盘上轻点某个卡片
platter, execute a complex
来执行一个复杂活动
action, and get right back to my
然后立刻反馈给我
So, let's take a look at the
下面 让我们来看一下
glanceable information.
可快速查看的信息
So, you can see we have this
你可以看到 我们再次
recipes app again.
使用到了 Recipes App
And, throughout the day, when
在这一整天中
I'm glancing at my wrist, I can
当我扫视手腕部位时
get a nice snippet of
我可以得到一条
information, right?
信息 对吧
I can see the recipe that I
我可以看到我今天晚些时候
might be cooking later today.
可能会烹饪的食谱
And, I can really easily decide
并且我可以轻松地决定
is this something I want to
我想不想做这道菜
make, or do I want to go out
或我今晚是否想外出
And, when I'm getting ready to
当我晚上准备好
go home in the evening, I can
要回家时 我可以
really easily tap on it to dive
轻松地轻点它
into this app and see, do I need
来深入浏览这个 App
to stop at the grocery store on
看看我是否需要在回家路上
my way home?
去一趟杂货店
So, if you're trying to provide
因此 如果你想为用户
glanceable information to the
提供可快速浏览的信息
user, there's a few things that
那么你需要记住
you want to keep in mind.
以下这些内容
Make sure that you're surfacing
确保你在你的
the most critical information in
Relevant Shortcut 中显示的
your relevant shortcuts.
是最关键的内容
This is the content that users
因为这是用户每天
are going to see at a wrist
在抬起手腕时
raise throughout the day, and
将看到的内容
this is the content that they
这是他们想
really want to see right on
立刻在表盘上
their watch face.
看到的内容
When the user taps on your
当用户轻点你的
relevant shortcut, it should be
Relevant Shortcut
opening up into a location
就应该打开你的 App 内的
within your app, and providing
一个位置 并为他们提供
them additional details.
额外的信息
Accidental taps on the Siri
也的确有不小心轻点了
watch face do happen, and so,
Siri 表盘的情况
you want to make sure you're not
在这种情况下 你一定想确认你没有
kicking off any long-running
开始任何用户不知情的
background task that the user
长时间运行的
isn't aware of.
后台任务
And, like Paul mentioned
正如 Paul 之前提到的
earlier, the system will
系统会自动给你
automatically be giving you an
一个附加的
additional background refresh
后台刷新任务
task to go provide new content.
让你提供新的内容
Take advantage of this, so you
请利用好这一性能
make sure you have relevant and
这样你就能确保
interesting content available on
可以在 Siri 表盘上
the Siri watch face.
显示相关的有趣内容
And, whenever you get new data,
而且 每当你得到新数据
whether that be through this
不论它是否
background refresh task, because
经过后台刷新
you've gone to the network and
因为你已经联网
downloaded new data, or because
并下载了新的数据
the user has started using your
或者由于用户已经开始使用你的 App
app, make sure that you provide
确保你提供的
new relevant shortcuts the
新的 Relevant Shortcut
system can always be surfacing
总能在用户抬起手腕时
the most interesting content to
让系统显示
the user right on a wrist raise.
最有趣的内容
And finally, if the information
最后 如果你想要
that you're trying to surface is
及时显示信息
timely, indicate that to us
请通过 Relevance Provider
through the relevance providers,
向我们发送指示
so the system can surface your
以便系统可以
content, again, when it's most
在最合适的时间显示你的内容
And so, that is glanceable
这就是快速可浏览信息
Now, let's talk a little bit
现在 让我们再谈一下
about tappable actions on the
Siri 表盘上的轻点动作
So, you can see we have this
大家可以看到我们再次
fitness trainer app again.
使用了这个 Fitness Trainer App
And, I can really easily, right
在我的手腕上
on my wrist, get this reminder
我可以轻松得到
that I need to go out for my
我需要出去跑步的提醒
And tapping on it, I get this
轻点它 我就会得到
nice confirmation to make sure
确认 来确定这就是
that this is the actual action
我想要执行的实际指令
And, in two taps, I can start
轻点两下 我就可以开始
this workout.
体能训练了
I don't need to spend time
我不用花费时间
digging through apps to find
去众多 App 里
this particular fitness trainer
寻找这个 Fitness Trainer App
app, and start-- kick off my
就可以开始进行我的体能训练
workout.
我可以在我的表盘上
right from my watch face, kick
轻松地轻点两下
off this workout.
就开始体能训练
So, if you're providing tappable
如果你提供了轻点指令
actions, a few things to keep in
请记住以下几点
Your intents are running within
你的 Intent 是在你的
your Siri extension.
Siri 扩展程序内运行的
And, this allows the system to
这就允许系统在后台
automatically run your intents
自动运行你的 Intent
in the background, so the user
这样用户就再也不用
never has to leave the Siri
离开 Siri 表盘
watch face to go run your
来运行你的指令了
We always display the standard
我们只展示标准的
system confirmation UI, so that
系统确认 UI
users know the action they're
这样用户就知道他们要
going to run, and we can make
运行的指令是什么
sure this is what they want to
我们可以确定这就是他们
perform.
想做的
You also want to make sure that
你也想确认
the relevant shortcuts that
你创建的捷径
you're creating are fully
是被完全指定的
specified, so that your intents
这样你的
extension can handle them
Intent 扩展程序就可以
without any additional user
在无需任何其他用户确认的情况下
confirmation.
处理它
So that when the user taps on
因此当用户轻点
one of these relevant shortcuts
Siri 表盘上的这些
on the Siri watch face, we don't
Relevant Shortcut 时
need to open up your app to
我们无需打开你的 App
continue and get, you know,
来从用户处
additional information from the
继续获取附加信息
We can kick off your SiriKit
我们可以开始运行你的
extension, run it in the
SiriKit 扩展程序
background, and the user can get
在后台运行它
on with their day.
用户就可以在当天获取它
And, you want to be providing
你肯定也想在你的 App 内
commonly used tasks within your
提供像 Relevant Shortcut 一样的
app as relevant shortcuts.
日常使用任务
These are the kind of tasks that
这些是用户经常使用
users are using your apps a lot
你的 App 的原因
for, and that they want to have
也是为什么他们想要
really quick and easy access to
从表盘上轻松快速地
from the watch face.
获取信息的原因
And, you also want to make sure
你也想要确认
that you're providing relevant
你能够经常提供
shortcuts often.
Relevant Shortcut
You may not know the last time
你可能不知道
that you provided relevant
你上次向系统提供
shortcuts to the system is, and
Relevant Shortcut 是什么时候
you want to make sure that your
而且你想要确认
users can always access your
你的用户总能从
actions right from the Siri
Siri 表盘上得到
watch face.
你的指令
If you're going to be providing
如果你要在 App 开始运行时
these when your app starts up,
提供这些内容
do it on a background thread so
请在后台线程操作
you're not slowing down your app
这样你就不会降低 App 的运行速度
So, we've talked a lot about
我们讨论了很多关于
relevant shortcuts, and the ways
Relevant Shortcut 的内容
that you can surface your
以及很多你可以在
information and actions right on
Siri 表盘上显示
the Siri watch face.
正确内容的方式
You want to make sure that
你需要确认你提供的
you're also providing relevant
内容是相关的
and engaging content.
并且吸引人的
This is the kind of content that
这是用户想要在
users want to see right on a
抬起手腕时立刻看到的内容
wrist raise, and the kind of
是我们想在 Siri 表盘上
content that we are surfacing on
显示的内容
the Siri watch face, and trying
也是我们想要
to promote to the top.
放在顶部的内容
The richest experience happens
当你有了 App
when you have a watchOS app.
你会得到最为丰富的体验
This is when the system can give
系统可以给你
you additional background
附加后台刷新任务
refresh tasks, and there's no
并且从用户轻点任意一个
latency between the user tapping
Relevant Shortcut
on one of the relevant
到我们开始执行指令之前
shortcuts, and us beginning
不会有任何的延迟
If you have any questions, we
如果大家有什么疑问
have a lab later today.
我们今晚还有一个实验室活动
We would love to talk to you
我们很乐意和各位谈谈
guys about relevant shortcuts
有关 Relevant Shortcut
and the Siri watch face.
和 Siri 表盘的内容
And, we're really excited to see
我们很期待看到
the kinds of experiences that
各位在表盘上创造出
you guys can create right on the
多种多样的体验
Thank you.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]